## **David Goodger**

651-442-2286 · goodger@python.org · david.goodger.org · linkedin.com/in/goodger/ · Minneapolis, MN

### Software Engineer/Architect · Systems Engineer/Analyst · Project Manager · Trainer

Software/Systems Engineer with professional experience in the medical device industry, the financial sector, and automation/manufacturing. Experience in project management and training. Recognized expert in the Python programming language. Extensive experience with markup languages for documentation, document processing, and data interchange. Cross-platform systems development experience, ranging from GUI desktop applications to web services to command-line tools.

Strengths include: effective communication between technical and non-technical/business audiences, public speaking, excellent writing and editing skills, thorough and tenacious problem solving. International experience, with written and spoken Japanese and French.

### **Technical Skills**

Programming Languages: Python (expert), Perl, Lisp, Visual Basic, C, C++, SQL, Bash.

**Development Methodologies:** Agile (Scrum, Extreme Programming), design patterns, refactoring, TDD/test-driven development, UML.

Operating Systems: Linux/UNIX/QNX/Solaris, Windows, Mac OS X.

**Documentation Technologies:** XML, XSL, SGML; HTML/XHTML, CSS; Docutils/reStructuredText; Unicode; document analysis, DTD design; document data processing.

### **Experience**

**Medtronic Inc.** (formerly Corventis), Mounds View, Minnesota, USA **Principal Systems Engineer.** 

January 2013 - present

- Projects: SEEQ mobile cardiac telemetry patch & CareLink cardiac patient monitoring service.
- Systems & data analysis.
- Software systems requirements development.
- Agile Scrum Product Owner.

**Programmer/Analyst.** Developed desktop GUI software for an electronic medical device system (SEEQ mobile cardiac telemetry patch). Technologies: Python, wxPython GUI toolkit, USB communication, web services, Dropbox integration.

GUI toolkits. (Full-time employee July 2005 – December 2008; consultant December 2008 – June 2012)

**Independent Consultant**, Montréal, Québec, Canada **Programmer/Analyst, Trainer, Systems Administrator.** 

December 2008 – January 2013

CDP Capital Inc., Montréal, Québec, Canada

**Programmer/Analyst.** Developed software tools for investment data analysis, including foreign exchange order management system and index fund management software. Technologies: Python, wxPython & tkInter

July 2005 – June 2012

**Python Software Foundation**, remote & Chicago, Illinois, USA December 2008 – September 2009 **Conference Coordinator.** Chaired the PyCon 2009 & 2008 Python community conferences, working (mostly remotely) with volunteer organizers and professional meeting planners. Chaired PyCon 2008 as a volunteer. **Member of the Board of Directors** (elected volunteer, February 2006 – July 2009)

## **Open-Source Projects**

Docutils: Documentation Utilities (<a href="http://docutils.sourceforge.net">http://docutils.sourceforge.net</a>) — project coordinator and architect

Polyform Puzzler (http://puzzler.sourceforge.net/) — project coordinator and architect

**Python** (the programming language, <a href="http://www.python.org">http://www.python.org</a>) — contributing developer; author or co-author of several Python Enhancement Proposals (<a href="http://www.python.org/peps/">http://www.python.org</a>)

### **Additional Relevant Experience**

ELM Machine Service Inc., Cambridge, Ontario, Canada

**Consulting Developer.** Developed a control panel and data acquisition application for a PLC-based industrial gauge system, using open-source rapid application development tools (Python, wxPython, Boa Constructor).

ATS Automation Tooling Systems Inc., Cambridge, Ontario, Canada

**Systems Administrator & Software Developer.** In charge of network and server systems in a mixed (Windows & QNX) environment, office and production facility with over 100 workstations. Developed engineering data processing applications & system maintenance solutions.

Rikai Ltd., Tokyo, Japan

President and Founder. Software development & information technology consulting.

Uniscope, Inc., Tokyo, Japan

**Operations Manager & Technical Team Leader; Developer.** Project & personnel management; research & development; analysis, design, and development of document processing, workflow, relational and object database, intranet, and internet systems; systems administration (Unix/Solaris, Windows platforms).

Embassy of Canada, Tokyo, Japan

**Network Systems Administrator & User Support Manager.** Systems administration, user support, training, programming, & troubleshooting (150 Windows clients, Unix servers).

Gunma Prefectural Board of Education (Japan Exchange & Teaching Program), Gunma, Japan Assistant English Teacher

#### **Education & Certificates**

# **Bachelor of Science, Major in Computer Science**

McGill University, Montréal, Québec, Canada

### **Certified Scrum Product Owner**

Scrum Alliance, Minneapolis, MN

# Japanese-Language Proficiency Test, Level 2

Japan Foundation & Japan Educational Exchanges and Services, Tokyo, Japan

## **Publications**

Hello World! Computer Programming for Kids and Other Beginners (Manning, 2009) — Technical Editor

Python For Dummies (Wiley, 2006) — Technical Editor

Python Cookbook, Second Edition (O'Reilly & Associates, 2005) — contributor (section 1.23)

Python Cookbook (O'Reilly & Associates, 2002) — contributor (sections 15.4 & 2.3)

**Professional Linux Programming** (Wrox Press, 2000) — author of Chapter 15, "Python," a programmer's introduction to the Python programming language

## **Keynote Presentations & Tutorials**

Python in India — Keynote presentation (PyCon India, Bangalore, India, 2010)

wxPython I: Introduction to GUI Programming & wxPython II: GUI Programming and MVC — Tutorials (PyCon 2010, Atlanta GA; PyCon 2008, Chicago IL)

How to Become an Invited Speaker — Keynote presentation (RuPy 2009, Poznan, Poland)

Code Like a Pythonista: Idiomatic Python — Tutorial (PyCon 2007, Dallas, Texas; OSCON 2007, Portland, Oregon)

Text and Data Processing — Tutorial (PyCon 2006, Dallas Texas)